{
  "decks": {
    "Norsk Vocab": {
      "cards": [
        {
          "question": "en nisse",
          "answer": "um duende",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:00:05.691300"
        },
        {
          "question": "um duende",
          "answer": "en nisse",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:00:19.268614"
        },
        {
          "question": "å våkne",
          "answer": "N: Bli bevisst igjen etter søvn.\nE: to wake (up)\nP: acordar",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:02:11.878781"
        },
        {
          "question": "E: to wake (up)\nP: acordar",
          "answer": "å våkne\nN: Bli bevisst igjen etter søvn.\nE: to wake (up)\nP: acordar",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:02:28.713619"
        },
        {
          "question": "står opp",
          "answer": "N: Går ut av senga; begynner dagen (presens av «å stå opp»).\nE: gets up; gets out of bed\nP: levanta-se",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:03:55.844309"
        },
        {
          "question": "N: Går ut av senga; begynner dagen\nE: gets up; gets out of bed\nP: levanta-se",
          "answer": "står opp",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:04:11.411241"
        },
        {
          "question": "et rundtstykke",
          "answer": "N: Lite, rundt porsjonsbrød; småbrød.\nE: bread roll\nP: pãozinho",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:04:30.409883"
        },
        {
          "question": "N: Lite, rundt porsjonsbrød; småbrød.\nE: bread roll\nP: pãozinho",
          "answer": "et rundstykke",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:04:52.264736"
        },
        {
          "question": "ei brødskive",
          "answer": "N: En skive av et brød (én «slice»).\nE: a slice of bread\nP: uma fatia de pão",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:05:16.759506"
        },
        {
          "question": "E: a slice of bread\nP: uma fatia de pão",
          "answer": "ei brødskive",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:05:30.087573"
        },
        {
          "question": "good morning - good evening - good night",
          "answer": "god morgen - god kveld - god natt",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:06:31.451696"
        },
        {
          "question": "Corn flakes",
          "answer": "ei frokostblanding",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:07:00.150830"
        },
        {
          "question": "jam, marmalade",
          "answer": "et syltetøy",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:07:18.139334"
        },
        {
          "question": "skuffet",
          "answer": "N: Føler seg misfornøyd fordi noe ikke ble som håpet; adjektiv (perf.part. av «å skuffe»).\nE: disappointed; let down\nP: desapontado(a); desiludido(a)",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:10:21.838759"
        },
        {
          "question": "E: disappointed; let down\nP: desapontado(a); desiludido(a)",
          "answer": "skuffet",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:10:32.343740"
        },
        {
          "question": "P: ela olha pela janela",
          "answer": "hun ser ut av vinduet",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:11:49.911881"
        },
        {
          "question": "i hvert fall",
          "answer": "N: Uttrykk som betyr «minst» eller «uansett; i alle fall».\nE: at least; in any case / anyway\nP: pelo menos; de qualquer forma / em todo caso",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:12:27.642335"
        },
        {
          "question": "N: Uttrykk som betyr «minst» eller «uansett; i alle fall».\nE: at least; in any case / anyway\nP: pelo menos; de qualquer forma / em todo caso",
          "answer": "i hvert fall",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:12:39.644368"
        },
        {
          "question": "E: at least; in any case / anyway\nP: pelo menos; de qualquer forma / em todo caso",
          "answer": "i hvert fall",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:12:54.156455"
        },
        {
          "question": "E: the dresser; the chest of drawers\nP:  a cómoda (PT)",
          "answer": "en kommode",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:14:20.761825"
        },
        {
          "question": "N: Lukket oppbevaringsmøbel med dører\nE: a cabinet/cupboard\nP: um armário",
          "answer": "et skap",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:14:46.866988"
        },
        {
          "question": "N: Møbel man sitter på, med sete og ryggstøtte.\nE: a chair\nP: uma cadeira",
          "answer": "en stol",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:15:09.430066"
        },
        {
          "question": "N: Kjøkkenapparat med kokeplater/platetopp og stekeovn i ett.\nE: stove; cooker (UK); range\nP: fogão (o forno é “forno”)",
          "answer": "en komfyr",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:16:31.355550"
        },
        {
          "question": "E: a bookcase / bookshelf\nP: uma estante (de livros)",
          "answer": "bokhylle",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:16:56.013990"
        },
        {
          "question": "E: a refrigerator / a fridge\nP: um frigorífico (PT)",
          "answer": "et kjøleskap",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:17:19.922845"
        },
        {
          "question": "Como comprimentar alguem que nunca mais viste",
          "answer": "Hyggelig å treffe/møte deg",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:20:13.966943"
        },
        {
          "question": "responder quando esta tudo normal, nem bom nem mal - depois de uma pergunta \"hvordan går det?\"",
          "answer": "takk, ikke så verst",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:21:19.012414"
        },
        {
          "question": "E: rude; impudent; cheeky\nP: insolente; mal-educado; atrevido (pejorativo)",
          "answer": "N: frekk\nN: Uoppdragen, uhøflig; freidig/kjekk på en negativ måte.",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:25:52.967074"
        },
        {
          "question": "N: Uttrykk som betyr «trist/leit; beklagelig».\nE: it’s a pity / that’s a shame / too bad\nP: é pena; que pena; é uma lástima",
          "answer": "**det er synd**",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:27:01.214349"
        },
        {
          "question": "N: Søke/forsøke å finne noe; se rundt for å oppdage det.\nE: to look for / search for something\nP: procurar algo",
          "answer": "å lete etter noe",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:28:08.500528"
        },
        {
          "question": "E: an editor (news/media/book)\nP: um editor / uma editora",
          "answer": "en redaktør",
          "created": "2025-11-01T23:49:11.914528"
        }
      ],
      "created": "2025-10-03T00:23:05.932293",
      "last_studied": null,
      "stats": {
        "total_studies": 0,
        "total_time": 0
      }
    },
    "Portugues Vocab": {
      "cards": [],
      "created": "2025-10-03T00:23:13.553411",
      "last_studied": null,
      "stats": {
        "total_studies": 0,
        "total_time": 0
      }
    },
    "English Vocab": {
      "cards": [
        {
          "question": "another word for begin",
          "answer": "commence",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:25:20.557433"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"make up\"",
          "answer": "fabricate",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:25:46.813052"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"repeat\"",
          "answer": "reiterate",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:26:21.423270"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"leave out\"",
          "answer": "omit",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:27:15.013110"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for ask",
          "answer": "inquire",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:27:31.112018"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \" support\"",
          "answer": "substantiate",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:28:07.223480"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"see\"",
          "answer": "percieve",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:28:22.680682"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"communicate\"",
          "answer": "convey",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:28:54.532338"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"obtain\"",
          "answer": "acquire",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:29:19.472341"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"propose\"",
          "answer": "postulate",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:29:35.490386"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"boldness\"",
          "answer": "audacity",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:30:43.373145"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"patient\"",
          "answer": "tolerant",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:31:21.150731"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"articulate\"",
          "answer": "eloquent",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:31:49.190922"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"responsible\"",
          "answer": "accountable",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:32:13.088817"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"hardworking\"",
          "answer": "industrious",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:32:52.958791"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"avoid\"",
          "answer": "abstain",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:33:40.910434"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"silly , unimportant\"",
          "answer": "frivolous",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:34:29.718454"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"imitate\"",
          "answer": "emulate",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:46:48.712956"
        },
        {
          "question": "another word for \"spread\"",
          "answer": "disseminate",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:47:35.897367"
        },
        {
          "question": "Expression Used when you are ready and eager to listen to someone's ideas or information.",
          "answer": "\"I'm all ears\"",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:48:43.489607"
        },
        {
          "question": "Expression Means a situation is risky or happening at the very last possible moment,",
          "answer": "\"Cutting it close\"",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:49:10.237315"
        },
        {
          "question": "Expression Indicates it's now someone else's turn to act or make a decision",
          "answer": "\"The ball is in your court\"",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:49:47.387712"
        },
        {
          "question": "Expression means feeling a bit sick",
          "answer": "\"Under the weather\"",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:50:26.988279"
        },
        {
          "question": "Expression Used to ask someone to be patient with you.",
          "answer": "\"Bear with me\"",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:51:11.346927"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: To start a conversation or make people feel more comfortable.",
          "answer": "“Break the ice”\n\nExample: “To break the ice at the party, I said hello to the person next to me.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:52:07.588536"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: To do something in the easiest or cheapest way, often badly.",
          "answer": "“Cut corners” \n\nExample: “The company cut corners on safety to save money, which caused problems.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:54:12.614638"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: To describe something exactly right.",
          "answer": "“Hit the nail on the head” \n\nExample: “You’ve hit the nail on the head with your idea about the problem.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:54:39.637370"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: Something very easy to do.",
          "answer": "“Piece of cake” \n\nExample: “The test was a piece of cake; I finished it very quickly.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:55:00.166274"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: To be very expensive",
          "answer": "“Cost an arm and a leg”\n\nExample: “That new phone costs an arm and a leg; I can’t buy it now.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:55:26.160860"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: To try to do more than you can manage.",
          "answer": "“Bite off more than you can chew” \n\nExample: “By agreeing to do two big projects at once, I bit off more than I could chew.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:55:53.756430"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: To avoid talking about what’s important.",
          "answer": "“Beat around the bush” \n\nExample: “Please stop beating around the bush and tell me what happened.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:59:15.868501"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: To be upset about something that has already happened and can’t be changed.",
          "answer": "“Cry over spilled milk” \n\nExample: “Don’t cry over spilled milk; let’s focus on fixing the problem.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T00:59:40.001893"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: To organise yourself and improve your behaviour.",
          "answer": "“Get your act together”\n\nExample: “You need to get your act together if you want to pass this class.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T01:00:05.260976"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: To solve two problems with one action.",
          "answer": "“Kill two birds with one stone”\n\nExample: “By walking to work, I kill two birds with one stone: I save money and get exercise.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T01:00:30.821964"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: To reveal a secret by mistake.",
          "answer": "“Let the cat out of the bag” \n\nExample: “I let the cat out of the bag about the surprise party when I asked her what cake she likes.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T01:26:06.514216"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: To work late into the night.",
          "answer": "“Burn the midnight oil” \n\nExample: “I’ve been burning the midnight oil to finish this project before the deadline.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T01:26:39.584840"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: To do something difficult or unpleasant that you have been avoiding.",
          "answer": "“Bite the bullet” \n\nExample: “I finally bit the bullet and went to the dentist after waiting for months.”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T01:28:50.006620"
        },
        {
          "question": "Meaning: A way of wishing someone good luck, especially before a performance.",
          "answer": "“Break a leg” \n\nExample: “You’re going to do great in the play tonight. Break a leg!”",
          "created": "2025-10-03T01:29:44.564435"
        }
      ],
      "created": "2025-10-03T00:23:20.599694",
      "last_studied": null,
      "stats": {
        "total_studies": 0,
        "total_time": 0
      }
    },
    "DAT250": {
      "cards": [],
      "description": "",
      "created": "2025-11-22T01:08:31.845171",
      "last_studied": null,
      "stats": {
        "total_studies": 0,
        "total_time": 0
      }
    }
  },
  "settings": {
    "last_used_deck": null,
    "theme": "light",
    "study_mode": "sequential"
  },
  "tags": [],
  "study_history": []
}